[Bride's Revenge]
[انتقام العروس]
[Episode 14]
[الحلقة 14]
[A Gentle Knife Cuts Deeper Than Any Other]
[سكين لطيف يقطع أعمق من أي سكين آخر]
(How dare he use such despicable means to test me!)
(كيف يجرؤ على استخدام هذه الوسائل الحقيرة ليختبرني!)
(What a monster!)
(يا له من وحش!)
(I'll make sure you die a gruesome death!)
(سوف أتأكد من أنك تموت موتًا شنيعًا!)
[Mu's Residence]
[مقر إقامتنا]
Where did you get all that money
من أين لك كل هذا المال
to start your timber business?
لبدء عملك في مجال الأخشاب؟
I have my own ways.
لدي طرقي الخاصة.
Did you earn the money yourself?
هل كسبت المال بنفسك؟
Our family
عائلتنا
runs a proper business.
يدير عملًا مناسبًا.
The world has already changed.
لقد تغير العالم بالفعل.
You're up in your years.
أنت في سنواتك.
You should retire and return to the countryside
يجب عليك التقاعد والعودة إلى الريف
to live the rest of your life in peace.
لتعيش بقية حياتك بسلام.
Silence!
الصمت!
How did I raise such an ungrateful child like you?
كيف ربيت مثل هذا الطفل الناكر للجميل مثلك؟
Me? Ungrateful?
أنا؟  جاكرين للجميل؟
All of you
كلكم
have always preferred my younger brother over me!
لطالما فضلت أخي الأصغر علي!
No matter what I do,
بغض النظر عما أفعله ،
I'll always be ignored.
سوف يتم تجاهلي دائما.
To you, I'll always be inferior to him!
بالنسبة لك ، سأكون دائمًا أدنى منه!
Blame yourself for not being
إلقاء اللوم على نفسك لعدم وجودها
as good as your brother!
خير مثل أخيك!
If your brother were still alive,
إذا كان أخوك لا يزال على قيد الحياة ،
he would never do this to his mother!
لن يفعل هذا لوالدته!
That's all because
هذا كل شيء بسبب
I'm not your biological son!
أنا لست ابنك البيولوجي!
You…
أنت…
You know?
أنت تعرف؟
When I learned of my origins,
عندما علمت بأصولي ،
I finally understood
فهمت أخيرا
why I was never able
لماذا لم استطع ابدا
to get the same attention all these years.
للحصول على نفس الاهتمام طوال هذه السنوات.
What gives?
ما يعطي؟
This family is what it is today
هذه العائلة هي ما هي عليه اليوم
because of the foundation my father built!
بسبب الأساس الذي بناه والدي!
Yet the Mu Family treats me like I'm a charity case.
ومع ذلك ، تعاملني عائلة مو وكأنني حالة خيرية.
If my father were still alive,
إذا كان والدي لا يزال على قيد الحياة ،
he would never let me fend for myself
لم يسمح لي أبدًا بالاعتناء بنفسي
for all these years!
لكل هذه السنوات!
You can't say that!
لا يمكنك قول ذلك!
All these years,
كل هذه السنوات،
we've raised you
لقد قمنا بتربيتك
like our own son!
مثل ابننا!
We never mistreated you!
نحن لم نسئ معاملتك ابدا!
That's only because the Mu Family owes me!
هذا فقط لأن عائلة مو مدينة لي!
But it's fine now.
لكن كل شيء على ما يرام الآن.
No one can tell me what to do anymore.
لا أحد يستطيع أن يخبرني ماذا أفعل بعد الآن.
I will have what I want.
سأحصل على ما أريد.
(Ever since I married him,)
(منذ أن تزوجته)
(Mu Ancheng sealed)
(مختومة Mu Ancheng)
(Anhe's room,)
(غرفة آنه ،)
(claiming it would remind Madam of sad memories.)
(زاعمًا أنه سيذكر السيدة بذكريات حزينة).
(Something important must be hidden here.)
(يجب إخفاء شيء مهم هنا.)
(This is the suitcase)
(هذه هي الحقيبة)
(that contained the ransom for Anhe.)
(التي احتوت على فدية Anhe.)
[50 taels]
[50 تيل]
(No wonder)
(لا عجب)
(Mu Ancheng was able to fork out such a large sum of money)
(كان Mu Ancheng قادرًا على صرف مثل هذا المبلغ الكبير من المال)
(to pay for my dowry.)
(لأدفع مهرتي).
(This was the money that was supposed to save Anhe's life.)
(كان هذا هو المال الذي كان من المفترض أن ينقذ حياة آنه).
(I'm going to report this to the authority!)
(سأبلغ السلطة بذلك!)
(You'll be put into jail, Mu Ancheng!)
(ستوضع في السجن ، مو أنشنغ!)
(No.)
(لا.)
(I was the one who had the ransom)
(كنت أنا الذي حصل على الفدية)
(but was unable to save Anhe.)
(لكن لم يكن قادرًا على إنقاذ Anhe.)
(If I use this to accuse Mu Ancheng,)
(إذا استخدمت هذا لاتهام Mu Ancheng ،)
(it'll backfire on me just like what happened before.)
(سوف يأتي بنتائج عكسية علي مثلما حدث من قبل).
(I need the madam to find out)
(أحتاج سيدتي لمعرفة ذلك)
(that this money is in Mu Ancheng's hands all along.)
(أن هذا المال في يد Mu Ancheng طوال الوقت.)
Take all of these away.
خذ كل هذه بعيدا.
Yes.
نعم.
What is the meaning of this?
ما معنى هذا؟
Mother.
الأم.
Ancheng said
قال Ancheng
that you shouldn't bring these valuables with you
أنه لا يجب عليك إحضار هذه الأشياء الثمينة معك
back to the countryside
العودة الى الريف
and told me to take care of them for you.
وأخبرني أن أعتني بهم من أجلك.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
These banknotes
هذه الأوراق النقدية
belong to the Ye Family.
تنتمي إلى عائلة Ye.
I'll be taking them.
سوف آخذهم.
Don't you even think about it!
لا تفكر حتى في ذلك!
I know
أنا أعرف
Ancheng gave you these as your dowry
أعطتك Ancheng هذه كالمهر الخاص بك
out of his own pocket!
من جيبه!
They have nothing to do with you!
لا علاقة لهم بك!
These notes
هذه الملاحظات
have my family's exclusive stamp on them.
عليها ختم عائلتي الحصري.
Just like the ransom for Anhe.
تماما مثل فدية Anhe.
If you refuse to accept this,
إذا رفضت قبول هذا ،
then there's nothing I can do.
ثم لا يوجد شيء يمكنني القيام به.
Consider them a tribute from me for your retirement.
اعتبرهم تحية مني لتقاعدك.
(I was wondering)
(كنت أتساءل)
(where Ancheng got all that money.)
(حيث حصلت Ancheng على كل هذه الأموال).
(Could this really be the ransom for Anhe?)
(هل يمكن أن يكون هذا حقًا فدية لـ Anhe؟)
Put those things down.
ضع هذه الأشياء جانبا.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Yes.
نعم.
Madam,
سيدتي،
First Young Master sent word
أرسل السيد الشاب الأول كلمة
that the carriage is ready
أن العربة جاهزة
and asked when you will depart.
وسألك متى ستغادر.
I'm staying.
انا باق.
I'm not going anywhere!
لن أذهب إلى أي مكان!
Madam…
سيدتي…
He wants to leave me to rot in the countryside?
يريد أن يتركني أتعفن في الريف؟
I won't let him have his way!
لن أتركه يشق طريقه!
All right, all right. We won't leave.
حسنا حسنا.  لن نغادر.
We'll stay.
سنبقى.
[Mu's Residence]
[مقر إقامتنا]
This is a joint letter
هذه رسالة مشتركة
from all of the Mu Family's shopkeepers.
من جميع أصحاب المتاجر في Mu Family.
They think that you're underqualified
يعتقدون أنك غير مؤهل
and not ready
وغير جاهز
to take over the Mu Family's business yet.
لتولي أعمال عائلة Mu حتى الآن.
So they've signed this joint letter
لذا فقد وقعوا هذه الرسالة المشتركة
asking me to take the helm for you.
يطلب مني تولي دفة القيادة نيابة عنك.
Mother,
الأم،
didn't we agree
لم نتفق
that you would go back to the countryside
أنك ستعود إلى الريف
and I would take charge
وسوف أتحمل المسؤولية
of everything in the Mu Family?
من كل شيء في عائلة مو؟
With so many shopkeepers showing concern,
مع وجود الكثير من أصحاب المتاجر الذين يبدون قلقهم ،
I can't possibly leave.
لا يمكنني المغادرة.
So you're going to interfere until the end?
إذن أنت ستتدخل حتى النهاية؟
I'm just
انا فقط
safeguarding the business for you temporarily.
حماية الأعمال لك مؤقتًا.
Someday,
في يوم ما،
all of this will be yours.
كل هذا سيكون لك.
No need to be impatient.
لا داعي لفارغ الصبر.
The things in my room…
الأشياء في غرفتي ...
I'll send them to your room right away.
سأرسلهم إلى غرفتك على الفور.
We can rest assured with you in charge,
يمكننا أن نطمئن إلى أنك المسؤول ،
Mother.
الأم.
At least you know that.
على الأقل أنت تعرف ذلك.
(Anhe,)
(آنهي)
(I will use your mother to avenge you.)
(سأستخدم والدتك للانتقام منك).
♪The tangle of love and hate between us♪
تشابك الحب والكراهية بيننا
♪Caused me to regret it♪
جعلني أشعر بالندم ♪
♪I'm afraid we can't change our fate in this life♪
♪ أخشى أننا لا نستطيع تغيير مصيرنا في هذه الحياة ♪
♪I do not fear. I do not hide♪
♪ لا أخاف.  أنا لا أخفي ♪
♪I can no longer bear the pain♪
♪ لم أعد أستطيع تحمل الألم ♪
♪It grows as time passes♪
ينمو بمرور الوقت ♪
♪Time will not tell you♪
♪ الوقت لن يخبرك
♪That I have been missing you♪
♪ أنني اشتقت إليك
♪You are all I think about♪
♪ أنت كل ما أفكر فيه ♪
♪No matter♪
♪ لا يهم
♪How harshly♪
كيف قسوة ♪
♪Life treats me♪
الحياة تعالجني
♪I can only let go of my hate♪
♪ يمكنني فقط التخلي عن الكراهية ♪
♪Not my love♪
♪ مش حبي ♪
♪We promised each other life-long love♪
♪ وعدنا بعضنا البعض بالحب مدى الحياة
♪Hopefully, we will keep that promise♪
♪ آمل أن نفي بهذا الوعد